If these walls could talk... they would shriek!
Amityville II: The Possession is a horror film directed by Damiano Damiani.
Anthony and Dolores Montelli, along with their four children, move into their dream house in
Amityville and are immediately plagued by a string of paranormal experiences.
When the abusive Anthony wrongly places the blame on their children,
Dolores recruits a local Catholic priest to exorcise the house.
Father Adamsky, played by James Olson.
Anthony Montelli, played by Burt Young.
Delores Montelli, played by Rutanya Alda.
Sonny Montelli, played by Jack Magner.
Father Tom, played by Andrew Prine.
Patricia Montelli, played by Diane Franklin.
Amityville II: The Possession is a 1982 supernatural horror film directed by Damiano Damiani and
starring James Olson, Burt Young, Rutanya Alda, Jack Magner, and Diane Franklin.
It is an international co-production between Mexico and the United States.
The screenplay by Tommy Lee Wallace and Dardano Sacchetti is based on the
novel Murder in Amityville by the parapsychologist Hans Holzer.
It is the second film in the Amityville Horror film series and a loose prequel to The Amityville Horror (1979), set
at 112 Ocean Avenue and featuring the fictional Montelli family, loosely based on the DeFeo family.
It follows the Montelli family's decline under apparent
demonic forces present in their home.
Principal photography took place at the same Toms River, New Jersey residence featured in the first film,
while interiors were shot exclusively on soundstages at Estudios Churubusco in Mexico City.
After test screenings were completed, Damiani's original cut of the film was slightly truncated to tone down
its overt incestuous sexuality and a rape sequence, which audiences responded to unfavorably.
Released by Orion Pictures in the fall of 1982, Amityville II: The Possession received unfavorable reviews from critics, though some,
such as Roger Ebert, felt it was superior to its predecessor, an opinion that has been echoed by contemporary reviewers.
The film explores themes of child abuse, sibling
relationship, abusive father, exorcism, poltergeist.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.